<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title> | RE4 ECO</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.re4eco.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.re4eco.com</link>
	<description>We Manage Your E-Waste</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 11:20:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i1.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/cropped-ewaste1.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title> | RE4 ECO</title>
	<link>https://www.re4eco.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">169912969</site>	<item>
		<title>E-Waste Artifacts display in Mohana Mantra</title>
		<link>https://www.re4eco.com/e-waste-artifacts-display-in-mohana-mantra/</link>
					<comments>https://www.re4eco.com/e-waste-artifacts-display-in-mohana-mantra/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 17:14:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogroll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artifacts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-waste crafts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mohana mantra]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.re4eco.com/?p=9567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A step towards proper utilization of non-recyclable e-waste Why E-waste Artifacts…? Usually, E-waste can be simply classified into recyclable and non-recyclable e-waste. There are many e-waste recycling firms that can process and recycle recyclable e-waste. So, in that way, the recyclable e-waste is taken care of. But, what about the non-recyclable e-waste…? Well, according to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>A step towards proper utilization of non-recyclable e-waste</p></blockquote>
<h2><strong><em>Why E-waste Artifacts…?</em></strong></h2>
<p>Usually, E-waste can be simply classified into recyclable and non-recyclable e-waste. There are many e-waste recycling firms that can process and recycle recyclable e-waste. So, in that way, the recyclable e-waste is taken care of. But, what about the non-recyclable e-waste…?</p>
<p>Well, according to a study, almost 20% of the e-waste produced is non-recyclable which is huge. What happens to this non-recyclable e-waste…? In most of the cases, the recycling firms separate the non-recyclable e-waste from the recyclable e-waste and they usually dump it along with other waste. This can be quite hazardous to the environment. So, in order to minimize the environmental threat from non-recyclable e-waste, we put forth the idea of making some really cool artifacts out of it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" src="https://i0.wp.com/i.pinimg.com/originals/33/04/8c/33048ca5ee8f34bf8291a7435fe97020.jpg?resize=497%2C568&#038;ssl=1" width="497" height="568" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>Generally, Reduce, Reuse and recycle are the three essential Rs to keep our environment pollution-free. We just took it to the next level by adding another R to those three which is Recreate(creating artifacts out of non-recyclable e-waste).</p>
<h2><strong><em>E-Waste Artifacts in Mohana Mantra</em></strong></h2>
<p>So, as a first step of the utilization of the non-recyclable e-waste, we designed some artifacts that are made out of e-waste and displayed them in Mohana Mantra, a national level techno-cultural fest of Sree Vidyanikethan Engineering college. These e-waste artifacts stood as a center of attraction for the fest for which more than 15000 students from various colleges of the country came.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-9642 alignright" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/WhatsApp-Image-2019-10-17-at-10.21.03-PM.jpeg?resize=300%2C169&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/WhatsApp-Image-2019-10-17-at-10.21.03-PM.jpeg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/WhatsApp-Image-2019-10-17-at-10.21.03-PM.jpeg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/WhatsApp-Image-2019-10-17-at-10.21.03-PM.jpeg?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/WhatsApp-Image-2019-10-17-at-10.21.03-PM.jpeg?resize=1140%2C640&amp;ssl=1 1140w, https://i1.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/WhatsApp-Image-2019-10-17-at-10.21.03-PM.jpeg?resize=750%2C422&amp;ssl=1 750w, https://i1.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/WhatsApp-Image-2019-10-17-at-10.21.03-PM.jpeg?resize=600%2C338&amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i1.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/WhatsApp-Image-2019-10-17-at-10.21.03-PM.jpeg?w=1280&amp;ssl=1 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>We also collected feedback from the visitors about our e-waste artifacts which got tremendous response from the viewers. We also learned a few things which might be quite helpful for improving our idea further.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-9644 alignleft" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/WhatsApp-Image-2019-09-27-at-6.16.46-AM.jpeg?resize=169%2C300&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="169" height="300" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/WhatsApp-Image-2019-09-27-at-6.16.46-AM.jpeg?resize=169%2C300&amp;ssl=1 169w, https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/WhatsApp-Image-2019-09-27-at-6.16.46-AM.jpeg?resize=576%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 576w, https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/WhatsApp-Image-2019-09-27-at-6.16.46-AM.jpeg?resize=600%2C1067&amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/WhatsApp-Image-2019-09-27-at-6.16.46-AM.jpeg?w=720&amp;ssl=1 720w" sizes="(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>So, we can proudly say that, on a whole, our first step towards the utilization of the non-recyclable e-waste is a huge success and this success gave us the confidence to proceed further.</p>
<p>Finally, “RE4 &#8211; Reduce, Reuse, Recycle and Recreate”, we hope you embrace this recycling mantra in your lives and make the world a better place by making it e-waste free.</p>
<p>Let us Haste to reduce E-Waste….!!!!</p>
<p>&#8211;  Team RE4 ECO.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.re4eco.com/e-waste-artifacts-display-in-mohana-mantra/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9567</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>RE4- Reduce, Reuse, Recycle, Recreate</title>
		<link>https://www.re4eco.com/re4-reduce-reuse-recycle-recreate/</link>
					<comments>https://www.re4eco.com/re4-reduce-reuse-recycle-recreate/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 16:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recycling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.re4eco.com/?p=9526</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ What is RE4&#8230;? It is a known fact that India is one of the largest producers of e-waste producing nearly 2 metric tonnes of e-waste annually. And there is no reason that this situation is gonna get better in the near feature. With the introduction of new era technologies like 5G, humanoid robots, and many]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2> What is RE4&#8230;?</h2>
<p>It is a known fact that India is one of the largest producers of e-waste producing nearly 2 metric tonnes of e-waste annually. And there is no reason that this situation is gonna get better in the near feature.<br />
With the introduction of new era technologies like 5G, humanoid robots, and many more potential e-waste accumulators, India needs an efficient e-waste management system very badly.<br />
Before the emergence of modern technology, only certain industries were the potential producers of e-waste. But times have changed. Domestic e-waste is growing as huge as industrial e-waste which essentially demanded the need for management of this domestic e-waste.</p>
<p>So, as we see, there is a burning need for the effective management system for e waste. If you still think why should we recycle e waste, check out- <a href="https://www.re4eco.com/is-there-a-need-for-an-e-waste-management-firm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> Is there a need for an e-waste management system&#8230;?</a><br />
So, we came up with an idea of filling the gap between these domestic e-waste producers and e-waste recycling firms. So, we thought of creating an innovative online platform connecting these domestic e-waste producers and recycling firms.<br />
We are a team of seven young aspired to be entrepreneurs striving to see our venture on cards and we’ll make that happen in the near future.<br />
Finally,</p>
<p>“ Let’s make Haste to end e-waste…!!!”<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-9530 size-full" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/device-recycling.jpg?resize=3000%2C1997&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="3000" height="1997" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<h2>Why RE4&#8230;?</h2>
<p>It is so cool that we collect e waste from domestic sources and sell it to e waste recycling firms. But why do people tend to sell us their e waste&#8230;? Why should they place a request for collection of their e waste&#8230;?</p>
<p>Well, because, we pay them for the e waste they sell. Isn&#8217;t it cool to earn from something which you usually throw away in dustbin&#8230;? All you need to do is  just accumulate your e waste, take a picture of it and place a request in our website for the collection of that waste. Everything else will be taken care of by us. It&#8217;s just that simple.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.re4eco.com/re4-reduce-reuse-recycle-recreate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9526</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is there a need for an E-Waste management firm&#8230;?</title>
		<link>https://www.re4eco.com/is-there-a-need-for-an-e-waste-management-firm/</link>
					<comments>https://www.re4eco.com/is-there-a-need-for-an-e-waste-management-firm/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 16:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recycling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[re4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recycle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.re4eco.com/?p=9398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Why should we manage E-Waste in the first place&#8230;? With new cheap devices, society has reaped tremendous benefits. This explosive growth in the electronics industry, however, has led to a rapidly escalating issue of end-of-life (EOL) electronics or e-waste. In landfills or primitive recycling operations, toxic materials can be released from old electronic devices into]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Why should we manage E-Waste in the first place&#8230;?</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-9758 aligncenter" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/images-13.jpg?resize=500%2C270&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="500" height="270" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/images-13.jpg?resize=300%2C162&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/images-13.jpg?w=306&amp;ssl=1 306w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>With new cheap devices, society has reaped tremendous benefits. This explosive growth in the electronics industry, however, has led to a rapidly escalating issue of end-of-life (EOL) electronics or e-waste. In landfills or primitive recycling operations, toxic materials can be released from old electronic devices into the environment.</p>
<div id="mntl-sc-block_1-0-2" class="comp mntl-sc-block mntl-sc-block-html">
<p>E-waste is growing, and with that surge comes the need for effective electronics recycling programs. According to a January 2019 report from the World Economic Forum, E-waste is now the fastest-growing waste stream in the world, with an estimated waste stream of 48.5 million tonnes in 2018.</p>
</div>
<div id="mntl-sc-block_1-0-3" class="comp mntl-sc-block mntl-sc-block-adslot mntl-block">
<div id="mntl-block_3-0" class="comp mntl-block">
<div id="billboard2-sticky-dynamic_1-0" class="comp scads-to-load right-rail__item billboard-sticky billboard2-sticky-dynamic billboard-sticky--sc scads-stick-in-parent scads-ad-placed" data-height="600">
<div class="spacer">
<div id="billboard2-dynamic_1-0" class="comp billboard2-dynamic mntl-gpt-dynamic-adunit mntl-gpt-adunit gpt billboard dynamic" data-ad-width="300" data-ad-height="250">
<div id="billboard2" class="wrapper" data-type="billboard" data-pos="btf1" data-priority="3" data-sizes="[[300, 250], [300, 600], [300, 601], [160, 600], [300, 251], [2, 1], &quot;fluid&quot;]" data-rtb="true" data-targeting="null" data-auction-floor-id="3812bf03aa8847bb9a00988c73868cf0" data-auction-floor-value="250" data-google-query-id="CMqOwqDV6OQCFVehaAod6VoB5g">
<div id="google_ads_iframe_/479/thebalancesmb/balsmb_sustainability/billboard2_0__container__">People still seek information on TV recycling, computer recycling, and other programs that will help them responsibly get rid of unwanted equipment ​while minimizing any risk of data or identity theft.</div>
<div>The safe recycling of electronics is receiving increased attention from policymakers, industry, and consumers alike. This trend is good news because many consumers are still not sure how to safely dispose of old computers, smartphones or other electronic devices.</div>
<div></div>
<div>According to one report, nearly 75 percent of old electronics continues to be stored in households because of the unavailability of convenient recycling options. In order to understand the urge for an effective management of e-waste, let us see the present disposal methods of e-waste followed by individuals and their hazards.</div>
<h2>Improper disposal of e-waste</h2>
<p>As per reports, it is estimated that around 20-50 million tons of E-waste get generated every year which gets exported to different regions for disposal. A huge proportion of E-waste gets exported to China and African countries like Ghana for disposal and recycling. Because of improper disposal and poor recycling process, lot of pollutants including heavy metals like lead, cadmium and persistent organic pollutants gets released from E-waste which can affect the human lungs as they contaminate the air.</p>
<p>When exposed to such harmful gases released during the burning of E-waste, the human lungs can develop cancer and get affected by respiratory diseases. The tested pollutant samples by the researchers showed an increase in levels of ROS and IL-8 which lead to inflammation and oxidative stress in the lungs. Some samples of E-waste were found to release phthalates which can impact sexual reproduction.  Hazardous chemicals like chlorinated dioxins get released through E-waste which leads to cancer.</p>
<p>Also dumping of E-waste in landfills is done in many countries which result in soil pollution. E-waste recycling generates plenty of valuable resources such as iron, aluminum, copper and gold. It also contains certain heavy metals like lead, tin, bauxite, cadmium, etc. Instead of dumping or burning E-waste, proper recycling of the used electronic products can save these natural resources and also safeguard our environment from pollution.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div>When E-waste gets burned, they release poisonous gases including CO<sup>2</sup>, Sulphur-di-oxide which lead to air pollution and also affect the ozone layer of our atmosphere. The ozone layer is responsible for preventing the harmful Ultraviolet rays of the sun from reaching our earth. Due to the depletion of the ozone layer, there is global warming which can bring drastic changes to climatic patterns of our earth.</div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>Improper disposal of E-waste results in the release of hazardous chemicals like lead, chromium, mercury, chemical flame retardants and beryllium which is dangerous to soil and water. The hardware and computer server usually contain chromium, mercury, and cadmium, etc. while LCD screens and Flat-panel TVs have the lead. For safeguarding the natural resources such as social and water from such toxic chemicals, E-waste should be recycled properly instead of dumping or burning in remote areas.</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.re4eco.com/is-there-a-need-for-an-e-waste-management-firm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9398</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hazards of E-Waste for Environment</title>
		<link>https://www.re4eco.com/hazards-of-e-waste-for-environment/</link>
					<comments>https://www.re4eco.com/hazards-of-e-waste-for-environment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 04:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[re4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recycle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.re4eco.com/?p=9393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The growing problem of E-Waste E-Waste is one of the growing hazards that every developing country is facing these days. As there are many industries which are producing e-waste a lot in countries like India. But the problem is, there aren&#8217;t any management techniques for the effective management of large amounts of e-waste that is]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>The growing problem of E-Waste</h2>
<p>E-Waste is one of the growing hazards that every developing country is facing these days. As there are many industries which are producing e-waste a lot in countries like India. But the problem is, there aren&#8217;t any management techniques for the effective management of large amounts of e-waste that is being produced.</p>
<p>With the usage of electrical and electronic equipment (EEE) on the rise, the amount of <strong>electrical and electronic waste</strong> (e-waste) produced each day is equally growing enormously around the globe. Recycling of valuable elements contained in e-waste such as copper and gold has become a source of income mostly in the informal sector of developing or emerging industrialized countries.</p>
<p>However, primitive recycling techniques such as burning cables for retaining the inherent copper expose both adult and child workers as well as their families to a range of hazardous substances. E-waste-connected health risks may result from direct contact with harmful materials such as lead, cadmium, chromium, brominated flame retardants or polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs), from inhalation of toxic fumes, as well as from accumulation of chemicals in soil, water and food. In addition to its hazardous components, being processed, e-waste can give rise to a number of toxic by-products likely to affect human health. Furthermore, recycling activities such as the dismantling of electrical equipment may potentially bear an increased risk of injury.</p>
<p>So, we can conclude that the primitive recycling techniques of e-waste are no longer effective and there is a burning need to advance for modern e-waste recycling techniques.</p>
<h2>Why should we recycle E-Waste&#8230;?</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-9762 aligncenter" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-984719162.jpg?resize=390%2C203&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="390" height="203" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-984719162.jpg?resize=300%2C156&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-984719162.jpg?resize=1024%2C532&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-984719162.jpg?resize=768%2C399&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-984719162.jpg?resize=1536%2C798&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-984719162.jpg?resize=750%2C390&amp;ssl=1 750w, https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-984719162.jpg?resize=600%2C312&amp;ssl=1 600w, https://i2.wp.com/www.re4eco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-984719162.jpg?w=1540&amp;ssl=1 1540w" sizes="(max-width: 390px) 100vw, 390px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Many old electronic devices contain toxic substances that include lead, mercury, cadmium, beryllium, polyvinyl chloride, and chromium. When e-waste is tossed into landfills, these chemicals leach into the soil, polluting the groundwater as well as the air.</li>
<li>Electronics are made of components that contain valuable raw materials. Recycling old devices saves energy. It also means that fewer raw materials need to be drawn from nature to create new devices.</li>
<li>Reusing old devices prevents e-waste by keeping it out of landfills. It also saves the resources used to recycle them. Additionally, reusing electronics helps other, less-fortunate people in your community. So take your old devices to be refurbished (if possible) and give them a new life.</li>
<li>Finally, recycling saves raw materials that can be repurposed by producing new devices. As a result, energy is saved, pollution is reduced, and there are fewer greenhouse gas emissions released into the atmosphere.</li>
</ul>
<p>After knowing the answer to the question &#8211; &#8220;Why should we recycle E-Waste&#8230;?&#8221;, the next obvious question is, &#8220;What are the benefits of recycling E-Waste&#8230;?&#8221;</p>
<h2>The Benefits of Recycling E-Waste</h2>
<div id="mntl-sc-block_1-0-20" class="comp mntl-sc-block mntl-sc-block-html">
<p>Recycling e-waste has various environmental and economic benefits:</p>
</div>
<div id="mntl-sc-block_1-0-22" class="comp mntl-sc-block mntl-sc-block-html">
<ol>
<li>According to EPA, recycling one million laptops can save the energy equivalent of electricity that can run 3,657 U.S. households for a year. EPA also states that by recycling one million cell phones, we can recover 75 lbs of gold, 772 lbs of silver, and 35,274 lbs of copper and 33 lbs of palladium.</li>
<li>According to the Electronics TakeBack Coalition, it takes 1.5 tons of water, 530 lbs of fossil fuel and 40 Ibs of chemicals to manufacture a single computer and monitor.</li>
<li>81 per cent of energy associated with a computer is used during production and not during operation.</li>
<li>Electronics contains various toxic and hazardous chemicals and materials that are released into the environment if we do not dispose of them properly.</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div id="mntl-sc-block_1-0-25" class="comp mntl-sc-block mntl-sc-block-adslot mntl-block">Recycling e-waste enables us to recover various valuable metals and other materials from electronics, saving natural resources (energy), reducing pollution, conserving landfill space, and creating jobs.</div>
<div></div>
<div class="comp mntl-sc-block mntl-sc-block-adslot mntl-block">So, before throwing your E-Waste away in the dustbin, just think for a while about the adverse effects it can show on the environment.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.re4eco.com/hazards-of-e-waste-for-environment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9393</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
